<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Done for the lulz and science]]></description><link>https://twitter.com/theliverdr</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 04:33:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[On Water]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hey there, lovely folks! The 8th Ayurveda Day in India is just around the corner, and we're excited to share some information with you. We…]]></description><link>https://twitter.com/theliverdr/on-water/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://twitter.com/theliverdr/on-water/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hey there, lovely folks! The 8th Ayurveda Day in India is just around the corner, and we&apos;re excited to share some information with you. We want to clarify a few things about drinking water and its role in our daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, drinking water is a wonderful and essential part of our well-being, much like a delicious scoop of ice cream. It doesn&apos;t matter if you have water before, during, or after your meals, or whether you prefer sips or gulps – it&apos;s all about staying hydrated and enjoying your water the way you like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some believe in the power of warm or cold water for various health concerns, we&apos;d like to remind you that water, in itself, isn&apos;t a magical remedy. It&apos;s essential for life, helps transport nutrients, regulates body temperature, and plays a crucial role in bodily functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, when it comes to health issues like cold, cough, or fever, remember that these symptoms can have various causes. If you&apos;re feeling unwell, it&apos;s always a good idea to consult a doctor rather than relying solely on warm water sips. They can provide the expert guidance you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we&apos;d like to emphasize that the term &apos;indigestion&apos; is quite broad and simplifying a complex process. It&apos;s important to respect the intricate workings of our body&apos;s metabolic processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let&apos;s enjoy our water and stay healthy, just like we enjoy a delightful ice cream treat. Water is indeed vital, but it&apos;s not a cure-all, and it&apos;s always best to consult a healthcare professional when in doubt about your health. Stay well and hydrated, friends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/theliverdr/status/1721339149318537271&quot;&gt;Read Original Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On Jaggery]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let's chat about sweeteners for a moment. Jaggery, honey, and white sugar are all different options. Each of these has its unique qualities…]]></description><link>https://twitter.com/theliverdr/on-jaggery/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://twitter.com/theliverdr/on-jaggery/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:10:14 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s chat about sweeteners for a moment. Jaggery, honey, and white sugar are all different options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these has its unique qualities, but it&apos;s essential to remember that there&apos;s no clear winner among them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice between them often depends on personal preferences and dietary needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, whether you prefer the natural goodness of jaggery, the sweetness of honey, or the simplicity of white sugar, it&apos;s all about what suits you best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/theliverdr/status/1721388183374717342&quot;&gt;Read Original Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On Hepatitis B virus (HBV)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello there, I'd like to discuss an issue that's important to me and affects our community in Kerala, as well as other parts of India. It's…]]></description><link>https://twitter.com/theliverdr/on-hbv/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://twitter.com/theliverdr/on-hbv/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 22:10:14 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello there, I&apos;d like to discuss an issue that&apos;s important to me and affects our community in Kerala, as well as other parts of India. It&apos;s about the stigmatization of people with hepatitis B virus (HBV) infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my years of diagnosing and treating HBV patients, I&apos;ve encountered situations where individuals, including their own families, have treated them unfairly, and sadly, I recently witnessed a particularly distressing incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In India, HBV infections are often transmitted within families, despite the most common mode of transmission being quite different. This misunderstanding is the first issue. The more prevalent modes of transmission in India are vertical (from mother to children during pregnancy and childbirth) and horizontal (from parents to children during early childhood through close contact).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s crucial to know that HBV does not spread through the air, sharing utensils, sitting in the same room, or even hugging. This virus doesn&apos;t transfer through these means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s disheartening to see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;HBV-positive children sent away from home
Parents not allowed to interact with their own grandchildren
Women losing marriage prospects
Neighbors avoiding visits to infected individuals
Friends ceasing to play with HBV-positive kids&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, a young woman with well-controlled HBV had to marry an older, paralyzed man because educated Malayali men from matrimonial websites were hesitant to accept a perfectly healthy HBV-positive woman. Her tears in my office left me speechless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s vital to understand that an HBV diagnosis isn&apos;t a death sentence. Many patients with HBV don&apos;t develop liver disease and need only regular follow-up. Those with advanced disease can lead normal lives with long-term antiviral therapy. For those with sudden HBV flare-ups (reactivation), treatment is usually effective and leads to a cure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stigmatizing people with HBV is not appropriate, and it&apos;s disheartening to witness this in 2023. HBV infection and its complications, like liver disease and liver cancer, are preventable through vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s support and educate one another to eliminate the stigma associated with HBV. Knowledge and understanding are our allies in this endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/theliverdr/status/1720648576425250845&quot;&gt;Read Original Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>